[{"id":123,"deckId":6,"front":"各地","back":"each place; every place; various places; all parts (of the country, world, etc.)","reading":"かくち","example":"","exampleTranslation":"","partOfSpeech":"Noun","createdAt":"2025-04-04T00:07:22.447Z"},{"id":124,"deckId":6,"front":"確認","back":"confirmation; verification; validation; review; check; affirmation; identification","reading":"かくにん","example":"","exampleTranslation":"","partOfSpeech":"Noun, Suru verb, Transitive verb","createdAt":"2025-04-04T00:07:40.991Z"},{"id":125,"deckId":6,"front":"過去","back":"the past; bygone days","reading":"かこ","example":"","exampleTranslation":"","partOfSpeech":"Noun, Adverb (fukushi), Noun which may take the genitive case particle 'no'","createdAt":"2025-04-04T00:07:51.274Z"},{"id":126,"deckId":6,"front":"火災","back":"conflagration; fire","reading":"かさい","example":"","exampleTranslation":"","partOfSpeech":"Noun","createdAt":"2025-04-04T00:08:01.487Z"},{"id":127,"deckId":6,"front":"花壇","back":"flower bed","reading":"かだん","example":"","exampleTranslation":"","partOfSpeech":"Noun","createdAt":"2025-04-04T00:08:17.947Z"},{"id":128,"deckId":6,"front":"価値","back":"value; worth; merit","reading":"かち","example":"","exampleTranslation":"","partOfSpeech":"Noun","createdAt":"2025-04-04T00:08:34.589Z"},{"id":129,"deckId":6,"front":"課長","back":"section manager; section chief","reading":"かちょう","example":"","exampleTranslation":"","partOfSpeech":"Noun","createdAt":"2025-04-04T00:09:36.101Z"},{"id":130,"deckId":6,"front":"各国","back":"each country; every country; various countries; all countries","reading":"かっこく","example":"","exampleTranslation":"","partOfSpeech":"Noun","createdAt":"2025-04-04T00:09:57.360Z"},{"id":131,"deckId":6,"front":"活動","back":"activity (of a person, organization, animal, volcano, etc.); action; operation","reading":"かつどう","example":"","exampleTranslation":"","partOfSpeech":"Noun, Suru verb, Intransitive verb","createdAt":"2025-04-04T00:10:09.138Z"},{"id":133,"deckId":6,"front":"家庭","back":"home; household; family; hearth","reading":"かてい","example":"","exampleTranslation":"","partOfSpeech":"Noun","createdAt":"2025-04-04T00:10:22.960Z"},{"id":134,"deckId":6,"front":"花瓶","back":"(flower) vase","reading":"かびん","example":"","exampleTranslation":"","partOfSpeech":"Noun","createdAt":"2025-04-04T00:10:38.589Z"},{"id":135,"deckId":6,"front":"髪型","back":"hair style; coiffure; hairdo","reading":"かみがた","example":"","exampleTranslation":"","partOfSpeech":"Noun","createdAt":"2025-04-04T00:10:48.852Z"},{"id":136,"deckId":6,"front":"観客","back":"spectator; audience","reading":"かんきゃく","example":"","exampleTranslation":"","partOfSpeech":"Noun","createdAt":"2025-04-04T00:10:59.526Z"},{"id":137,"deckId":6,"front":"環境","back":"environment; surroundings; circumstances","reading":"かんきょう","example":"","exampleTranslation":"","partOfSpeech":"Noun","createdAt":"2025-04-04T00:11:09.291Z"},{"id":138,"deckId":6,"front":"関係","back":"relation; relationship; connection","reading":"かんけい","example":"","exampleTranslation":"","partOfSpeech":"Noun, Suru verb, Intransitive verb","createdAt":"2025-04-04T00:11:17.897Z"},{"id":139,"deckId":6,"front":"歓迎","back":"welcome; (warm) reception","reading":"かんげい","example":"","exampleTranslation":"","partOfSpeech":"Noun, Suru verb, Transitive verb","createdAt":"2025-04-04T00:11:27.697Z"},{"id":140,"deckId":6,"front":"感激","back":"deep emotion; impression; inspiration","reading":"かんげき","example":"","exampleTranslation":"","partOfSpeech":"Noun, Suru verb, Intransitive verb","createdAt":"2025-04-04T00:11:37.352Z"},{"id":141,"deckId":6,"front":"観光","back":"sightseeing; tourism","reading":"かんこう","example":"","exampleTranslation":"","partOfSpeech":"Noun, Suru verb, Transitive verb","createdAt":"2025-04-04T00:11:47.163Z"},{"id":142,"deckId":6,"front":"看護","back":"nursing; (army) nurse","reading":"かんご","example":"","exampleTranslation":"","partOfSpeech":"Noun, Suru verb, Transitive verb","createdAt":"2025-04-04T00:11:56.050Z"},{"id":143,"deckId":6,"front":"観察","back":"observation; survey; watching","reading":"かんさつ","example":"","exampleTranslation":"","partOfSpeech":"Noun, Suru verb, Transitive verb","createdAt":"2025-04-04T00:12:07.207Z"},{"id":144,"deckId":6,"front":"感謝","back":"thanks; gratitude; appreciation; thankfulness","reading":"かんしゃ","example":"","exampleTranslation":"","partOfSpeech":"Noun, Suru verb, Transitive verb, Intransitive verb","createdAt":"2025-04-04T00:12:17.702Z"},{"id":145,"deckId":6,"front":"関心","back":"concern; interest","reading":"かんしん","example":"","exampleTranslation":"","partOfSpeech":"Noun","createdAt":"2025-04-04T00:12:33.349Z"},{"id":146,"deckId":6,"front":"感心","back":"admiration; being impressed","reading":"かんしん","example":"","exampleTranslation":"","partOfSpeech":"Noun, Suru verb, Intransitive verb","createdAt":"2025-04-04T00:12:37.424Z"},{"id":147,"deckId":6,"front":"完成","back":"completion; perfection; accomplishment","reading":"かんせい","example":"","exampleTranslation":"","partOfSpeech":"Noun, Suru verb, Transitive verb, Intransitive verb","createdAt":"2025-04-04T00:12:49.344Z"},{"id":148,"deckId":6,"front":"乾燥","back":"dryness; aridity; drying (e.g. clothes); dehydration; desiccation","reading":"かんそう","example":"","exampleTranslation":"","partOfSpeech":"Noun, Suru verb, Transitive verb, Intransitive verb","createdAt":"2025-04-04T00:13:04.876Z"},{"id":149,"deckId":6,"front":"感想","back":"impressions; thoughts; feelings; reactions","reading":"かんそう","example":"","exampleTranslation":"","partOfSpeech":"Noun","createdAt":"2025-04-04T00:13:11.853Z"},{"id":150,"deckId":6,"front":"感動","back":"being deeply moved emotionally; excitement; passion; inspiration; deep emotion; strong impression","reading":"かんどう","example":"","exampleTranslation":"","partOfSpeech":"Noun, Suru verb, Intransitive verb","createdAt":"2025-04-04T00:13:29.042Z"},{"id":151,"deckId":6,"front":"館内","back":"inside a library, museum, cinema, etc.; on the premises","reading":"かんない","example":"","exampleTranslation":"","partOfSpeech":"Noun, Noun which may take the genitive case particle 'no'","createdAt":"2025-04-04T00:13:42.376Z"},{"id":152,"deckId":6,"front":"外出","back":"going out; outing; leaving (one's home, office, etc.)","reading":"がいしゅつ","example":"","exampleTranslation":"","partOfSpeech":"Noun, Suru verb, Intransitive verb","createdAt":"2025-04-04T00:13:56.146Z"},{"id":153,"deckId":6,"front":"外食","back":"eating out; dining out","reading":"がいしょく","example":"","exampleTranslation":"","partOfSpeech":"Noun, Suru verb, Intransitive verb","createdAt":"2025-04-04T00:14:05.552Z"},{"id":154,"deckId":6,"front":"画家","back":"painter; artist","reading":"がか","example":"","exampleTranslation":"","partOfSpeech":"Noun","createdAt":"2025-04-04T00:14:15.316Z"},{"id":155,"deckId":6,"front":"学部","back":"department (of a university); faculty; school; college","reading":"がくぶ","example":"","exampleTranslation":"","partOfSpeech":"Noun","createdAt":"2025-04-04T00:14:33.919Z"},{"id":156,"deckId":6,"front":"学期","back":"school term; semester","reading":"がっき","example":"","exampleTranslation":"","partOfSpeech":"Noun","createdAt":"2025-04-04T00:14:42.093Z"},{"id":157,"deckId":6,"front":"楽器","back":"musical instrument","reading":"がっき","example":"","exampleTranslation":"","partOfSpeech":"Noun, Noun which may take the genitive case particle 'no'","createdAt":"2025-04-04T00:14:47.835Z"},{"id":158,"deckId":6,"front":"我慢","back":"endurance; patience; perseverance; bearing (with something)","reading":"がまん","example":"","exampleTranslation":"","partOfSpeech":"Noun, Suru verb, Transitive verb, Intransitive verb","createdAt":"2025-04-04T00:15:01.144Z"},{"id":159,"deckId":6,"front":"気温","back":"(air) temperature","reading":"きおん","example":"","exampleTranslation":"","partOfSpeech":"Noun","createdAt":"2025-04-04T00:15:14.048Z"},{"id":160,"deckId":6,"front":"機械","back":"machine; mechanism","reading":"きかい","example":"","exampleTranslation":"","partOfSpeech":"Noun","createdAt":"2025-04-04T00:15:28.156Z"},{"id":161,"deckId":6,"front":"期間","back":"period; term; interval","reading":"きかん","example":"","exampleTranslation":"","partOfSpeech":"Noun","createdAt":"2025-04-04T00:15:38.427Z"},{"id":162,"deckId":6,"front":"企業","back":"enterprise; business; company; corporation","reading":"きぎょう","example":"","exampleTranslation":"","partOfSpeech":"Noun","createdAt":"2025-04-04T00:15:49.306Z"},{"id":163,"deckId":6,"front":"期限","back":"term; period; time frame","reading":"きげん","example":"","exampleTranslation":"","partOfSpeech":"Noun","createdAt":"2025-04-04T00:16:02.394Z"},{"id":164,"deckId":6,"front":"帰国","back":"return to one's country","reading":"きこく","example":"","exampleTranslation":"","partOfSpeech":"Noun, Suru verb, Intransitive verb","createdAt":"2025-04-04T00:16:16.669Z"},{"id":165,"deckId":6,"front":"記事","back":"article; news story; report; account","reading":"きじ","example":"","exampleTranslation":"","partOfSpeech":"Noun","createdAt":"2025-04-04T00:16:27.453Z"},{"id":166,"deckId":6,"front":"基礎","back":"foundation; basis","reading":"きそ","example":"","exampleTranslation":"","partOfSpeech":"Noun, Noun which may take the genitive case particle 'no'","createdAt":"2025-04-04T00:16:37.527Z"},{"id":167,"deckId":6,"front":"規則","back":"rule; regulation","reading":"きそく","example":"","exampleTranslation":"","partOfSpeech":"Noun","createdAt":"2025-04-04T00:16:47.247Z"},{"id":168,"deckId":6,"front":"期待","back":"expectation; anticipation; hope","reading":"きたい","example":"","exampleTranslation":"","partOfSpeech":"Noun, Suru verb, Transitive verb, Intransitive verb","createdAt":"2025-04-04T00:16:57.472Z"},{"id":169,"deckId":6,"front":"北側","back":"north side; north bank","reading":"きたがわ","example":"","exampleTranslation":"","partOfSpeech":"Noun","createdAt":"2025-04-04T00:17:06.826Z"},{"id":170,"deckId":6,"front":"帰宅","back":"returning home; going home; coming home; getting home","reading":"きたく","example":"","exampleTranslation":"","partOfSpeech":"Noun, Suru verb, Intransitive verb","createdAt":"2025-04-04T00:17:25.244Z"},{"id":171,"deckId":6,"front":"切符","back":"ticket","reading":"きっぷ","example":"","exampleTranslation":"","partOfSpeech":"Noun","createdAt":"2025-04-04T00:17:39.487Z"},{"id":172,"deckId":6,"front":"記念","back":"commemoration; celebration; remembrance; memory; honoring the memory of","reading":"きねん","example":"","exampleTranslation":"","partOfSpeech":"Noun, Suru verb, Transitive verb","createdAt":"2025-04-04T00:17:49.159Z"},{"id":173,"deckId":6,"front":"基本","back":"basics; fundamentals; basis; foundation","reading":"きほん","example":"","exampleTranslation":"","partOfSpeech":"Noun, Noun which may take the genitive case particle 'no'","createdAt":"2025-04-04T00:17:58.663Z"},{"id":174,"deckId":6,"front":"希望","back":"hope; wish; aspiration","reading":"きぼう","example":"","exampleTranslation":"","partOfSpeech":"Noun, Suru verb, Transitive verb","createdAt":"2025-04-04T00:18:11.136Z"},{"id":176,"deckId":6,"front":"競争","back":"competition; contest; rivalry; race","reading":"きょうそう","example":"","exampleTranslation":"","partOfSpeech":"Noun, Suru verb, Transitive verb, Intransitive verb","createdAt":"2025-04-04T00:18:24.993Z"},{"id":177,"deckId":6,"front":"共通","back":"common; shared; mutual","reading":"きょうつう","example":"","exampleTranslation":"","partOfSpeech":"Noun which may take the genitive case particle 'no', Na-adjective (keiyodoshi), Noun","createdAt":"2025-04-04T00:18:37.356Z"},{"id":178,"deckId":6,"front":"協力","back":"cooperation; collaboration; help; support","reading":"きょうりょく","example":"","exampleTranslation":"","partOfSpeech":"Noun, Suru verb, Intransitive verb","createdAt":"2025-04-04T00:18:52.340Z"},{"id":179,"deckId":6,"front":"距離","back":"distance; range; interval","reading":"きょり","example":"","exampleTranslation":"","partOfSpeech":"Noun","createdAt":"2025-04-04T00:19:02.802Z"},{"id":180,"deckId":6,"front":"記録","back":"record; document; minutes; recording; putting on record; keeping a record (of); writing down","reading":"きろく","example":"","exampleTranslation":"","partOfSpeech":"Noun, Suru verb, Transitive verb","createdAt":"2025-04-04T00:19:16.606Z"},{"id":181,"deckId":6,"front":"近所","back":"neighbourhood; neighborhood; vicinity","reading":"きんじょ","example":"","exampleTranslation":"","partOfSpeech":"Noun, Noun which may take the genitive case particle 'no'","createdAt":"2025-04-04T00:19:27.756Z"},{"id":182,"deckId":6,"front":"技術","back":"technology; engineering","reading":"ぎじゅつ","example":"","exampleTranslation":"","partOfSpeech":"Noun","createdAt":"2025-04-04T00:19:47.032Z"},{"id":183,"deckId":6,"front":"草花","back":"flower; flowering plant","reading":"くさばな","example":"","exampleTranslation":"","partOfSpeech":"Noun","createdAt":"2025-04-04T00:20:04.201Z"},{"id":184,"deckId":6,"front":"工夫","back":"devising (a way); contriving; inventing; thinking up; figuring out; coming up with; working out","reading":"くふう","example":"","exampleTranslation":"","partOfSpeech":"Noun, Suru verb, Transitive verb","createdAt":"2025-04-04T00:20:16.503Z"},{"id":185,"deckId":6,"front":"区別","back":"distinction; differentiation; discrimination; difference","reading":"くべつ","example":"","exampleTranslation":"","partOfSpeech":"Noun, Suru verb, Transitive verb","createdAt":"2025-04-04T00:20:38.692Z"},{"id":186,"deckId":6,"front":"苦労","back":"trouble; hardship; difficulty; labour; labor; toil; pains","reading":"くろう","example":"","exampleTranslation":"","partOfSpeech":"Noun, Suru verb","createdAt":"2025-04-04T00:20:53.406Z"},{"id":187,"deckId":6,"front":"苦労","back":"trouble; hardship; difficulty; labour; labor; toil; pains","reading":"くろう","example":"","exampleTranslation":"","partOfSpeech":"Noun, Suru verb","createdAt":"2025-04-04T00:22:22.328Z"},{"id":188,"deckId":6,"front":"訓練","back":"training; drill; practice; discipline","reading":"くんれん","example":"","exampleTranslation":"","partOfSpeech":"Noun, Suru verb, Transitive verb","createdAt":"2025-04-04T00:22:32.509Z"},{"id":189,"deckId":6,"front":"偶然","back":"coincidence; chance; accident; fortuity","reading":"ぐうぜん","example":"","exampleTranslation":"","partOfSpeech":"Noun, Na-adjective (keiyodoshi), Noun which may take the genitive case particle 'no'","createdAt":"2025-04-04T00:22:44.817Z"},{"id":190,"deckId":6,"front":"経営","back":"management; administration; operation; running (a business); conducting","reading":"けいえい","example":"","exampleTranslation":"","partOfSpeech":"Noun, Suru verb, Transitive verb","createdAt":"2025-04-04T00:23:03.853Z"},{"id":191,"deckId":6,"front":"計画","back":"plan; project; schedule; scheme; program; programme","reading":"けいかく","example":"","exampleTranslation":"","partOfSpeech":"Noun, Suru verb, Transitive verb","createdAt":"2025-04-04T00:24:25.427Z"},{"id":192,"deckId":6,"front":"警官","back":"police officer; policeman; constable","reading":"けいかん","example":"","exampleTranslation":"","partOfSpeech":"Noun","createdAt":"2025-04-04T00:24:38.356Z"},{"id":193,"deckId":6,"front":"携帯","back":"carrying (on one's person or in the hand)","reading":"けいたい","example":"","exampleTranslation":"","partOfSpeech":"Noun, Suru verb, Transitive verb","createdAt":"2025-04-04T00:25:24.950Z"},{"id":194,"deckId":6,"front":"経由","back":"going through; going via; going by way of","reading":"けいゆ","example":"","exampleTranslation":"","partOfSpeech":"Noun, Suru verb, Intransitive verb","createdAt":"2025-04-04T00:30:05.849Z"},{"id":195,"deckId":6,"front":"景色","back":"scenery; scene; landscape","reading":"けしき","example":"","exampleTranslation":"","partOfSpeech":"Noun","createdAt":"2025-04-04T00:30:31.138Z"},{"id":196,"deckId":6,"front":"結局","back":"after all; in the end; ultimately; eventually","reading":"けっきょく","example":"","exampleTranslation":"","partOfSpeech":"Adverb (fukushi)","createdAt":"2025-04-04T00:30:45.057Z"},{"id":197,"deckId":6,"front":"結構","back":"splendid; nice; wonderful; delightful; lovely; excellent; fine","reading":"けっこう","example":"","exampleTranslation":"","partOfSpeech":"Na-adjective (keiyodoshi)","createdAt":"2025-04-04T00:31:02.853Z"},{"id":198,"deckId":6,"front":"結婚","back":"marriage","reading":"けっこん","example":"","exampleTranslation":"","partOfSpeech":"Noun, Suru verb, Intransitive verb","createdAt":"2025-04-04T00:31:54.341Z"},{"id":199,"deckId":6,"front":"欠点","back":"fault; defect; flaw; weak point; weakness; shortcoming; drawback","reading":"けってん","example":"","exampleTranslation":"","partOfSpeech":"Noun","createdAt":"2025-04-04T00:32:58.728Z"},{"id":200,"deckId":6,"front":"健康","back":"health","reading":"けんこう","example":"","exampleTranslation":"","partOfSpeech":"Noun","createdAt":"2025-04-04T00:33:07.903Z"},{"id":201,"deckId":6,"front":"検査","back":"inspection (e.g. customs, factory); examination; test; check; scan (e.g. MRI, PET); audit","reading":"けんさ","example":"","exampleTranslation":"","partOfSpeech":"Noun, Suru verb, Transitive verb","createdAt":"2025-04-04T00:33:16.762Z"},{"id":202,"deckId":6,"front":"建設","back":"construction; establishment","reading":"けんせつ","example":"","exampleTranslation":"","partOfSpeech":"Noun, Suru verb, Transitive verb","createdAt":"2025-04-04T00:33:25.988Z"},{"id":203,"deckId":6,"front":"建築","back":"construction; architecture (of buildings)","reading":"けんちく","example":"","exampleTranslation":"","partOfSpeech":"Noun, Suru verb, Transitive verb","createdAt":"2025-04-04T00:33:38.762Z"},{"id":204,"deckId":6,"front":"芸術","back":"art; the arts","reading":"げいじゅつ","example":"","exampleTranslation":"","partOfSpeech":"Noun","createdAt":"2025-04-04T00:33:54.783Z"},{"id":205,"deckId":6,"front":"原因","back":"cause; origin; source","reading":"げんいん","example":"","exampleTranslation":"","partOfSpeech":"Noun, Suru verb, Intransitive verb","createdAt":"2025-04-04T00:34:20.635Z"},{"id":206,"deckId":6,"front":"原稿","back":"manuscript; copy; draft; notes; contribution","reading":"げんこう","example":"","exampleTranslation":"","partOfSpeech":"Noun","createdAt":"2025-04-04T00:34:31.644Z"},{"id":207,"deckId":6,"front":"言語","back":"language","reading":"げんご","example":"","exampleTranslation":"","partOfSpeech":"Noun","createdAt":"2025-04-04T00:34:45.026Z"},{"id":208,"deckId":6,"front":"減少","back":"decrease; reduction; decline","reading":"げんしょう","example":"","exampleTranslation":"","partOfSpeech":"Noun, Suru verb, Transitive verb, Intransitive verb, Noun which may take the genitive case particle 'no'","createdAt":"2025-04-04T00:34:57.947Z"},{"id":209,"deckId":6,"front":"講演","back":"lecture; address; speech","reading":"こうえん","example":"","exampleTranslation":"","partOfSpeech":"Noun, Suru verb, Transitive verb, Intransitive verb","createdAt":"2025-04-04T00:35:12.550Z"},{"id":210,"deckId":6,"front":"高温","back":"high temperature","reading":"こうおん","example":"","exampleTranslation":"","partOfSpeech":"Noun","createdAt":"2025-04-04T00:35:25.220Z"},{"id":211,"deckId":6,"front":"効果","back":"effect; effectiveness; efficacy; result","reading":"こうか","example":"","exampleTranslation":"","partOfSpeech":"Noun, Noun which may take the genitive case particle 'no'","createdAt":"2025-04-04T00:35:41.039Z"},{"id":212,"deckId":6,"front":"交換","back":"exchange; interchange; switching; reciprocity; barter; substitution; replacement; clearing (of checks, cheques)","reading":"こうかん","example":"","exampleTranslation":"","partOfSpeech":"Noun, Suru verb, Transitive verb","createdAt":"2025-04-04T00:35:52.404Z"},{"id":213,"deckId":6,"front":"後期","back":"latter period; second half; late stage; third trimester; second semester","reading":"こうき","example":"","exampleTranslation":"","partOfSpeech":"Noun, Noun which may take the genitive case particle 'no'","createdAt":"2025-04-04T00:36:02.976Z"},{"id":214,"deckId":6,"front":"講義","back":"lecture","reading":"こうぎ","example":"","exampleTranslation":"","partOfSpeech":"Noun, Suru verb, Transitive verb","createdAt":"2025-04-04T00:36:13.244Z"},{"id":215,"deckId":6,"front":"公共","back":"public (facilities, service, etc.); communal","reading":"こうきょう","example":"","exampleTranslation":"","partOfSpeech":"Noun which may take the genitive case particle 'no', Noun","createdAt":"2025-04-04T00:36:24.753Z"},{"id":216,"deckId":6,"front":"工業","back":"(manufacturing) industry","reading":"こうぎょう","example":"","exampleTranslation":"","partOfSpeech":"Noun","createdAt":"2025-04-04T00:36:35.012Z"},{"id":217,"deckId":6,"front":"航空","back":"aviation; flying","reading":"こうくう","example":"","exampleTranslation":"","partOfSpeech":"Noun","createdAt":"2025-04-04T00:36:45.542Z"},{"id":218,"deckId":6,"front":"広告","back":"advertisement; advertising","reading":"こうこく","example":"","exampleTranslation":"","partOfSpeech":"Noun, Suru verb, Transitive verb","createdAt":"2025-04-04T00:36:59.595Z"},{"id":219,"deckId":6,"front":"工事","back":"construction work","reading":"こうじ","example":"","exampleTranslation":"","partOfSpeech":"Noun, Suru verb, Transitive verb, Intransitive verb","createdAt":"2025-04-04T00:37:07.374Z"},{"id":220,"deckId":6,"front":"紅茶","back":"black tea","reading":"こうちゃ","example":"","exampleTranslation":"","partOfSpeech":"Noun","createdAt":"2025-04-04T00:37:17.576Z"},{"id":221,"deckId":6,"front":"交通","back":"traffic; transportation; communication; exchange (of ideas, etc.); intercourse","reading":"こうつう","example":"","exampleTranslation":"","partOfSpeech":"Noun, Suru verb","createdAt":"2025-04-04T00:37:26.892Z"},{"id":222,"deckId":6,"front":"行動","back":"action; conduct; behaviour; behavior; mobilization; mobilisation","reading":"こうどう","example":"","exampleTranslation":"","partOfSpeech":"Noun, Suru verb, Intransitive verb, Noun which may take the genitive case particle 'no'","createdAt":"2025-04-04T00:37:38.049Z"},{"id":223,"deckId":6,"front":"家庭","back":"home; household; family; hearth","reading":"かてい","example":"","exampleTranslation":"","partOfSpeech":"Noun","createdAt":"2025-04-04T00:40:11.006Z"},{"id":224,"deckId":6,"front":"競争","back":"competition; contest; rivalry; race","reading":"きょうそう","example":"","exampleTranslation":"","partOfSpeech":"Noun, Suru verb, Transitive verb, Intransitive verb","createdAt":"2025-04-04T00:40:20.891Z"},{"id":3,"deckId":1,"front":"椅子","back":"chair; seat; stool; bench","reading":"いす","example":"","exampleTranslation":"","partOfSpeech":"Noun","createdAt":"2025-04-01T05:37:28.287Z"},{"id":19,"deckId":1,"front":"奥","back":"inner part; interior; back (of a drawer, one's throat, etc.); depths (e.g. of a forest); recesses (e.g. of a cave); heart; end (of a road, garden, etc.)","reading":"おく","example":"","exampleTranslation":"","partOfSpeech":"Noun","createdAt":"2025-04-01T07:36:57.946Z"},{"id":35,"deckId":1,"front":"城","back":"castle","reading":"しろ","example":"","exampleTranslation":"","partOfSpeech":"Noun","createdAt":"2025-04-01T07:53:52.848Z"},{"id":1,"deckId":1,"front":"食べる","back":"to eat","reading":"たべる","example":"私はりんごを食べる。","exampleTranslation":"I eat an apple.","partOfSpeech":"Verb (Group 2)","createdAt":"2025-04-01T05:36:14.150Z"},{"id":2,"deckId":1,"front":"図書館","back":"library","reading":"としょかん","example":"図書館で本を借りました。","exampleTranslation":"I borrowed a book from the library.","partOfSpeech":"Noun","createdAt":"2025-04-01T05:36:14.150Z"},{"id":58,"deckId":1,"front":"十分","back":"enough; sufficient; plenty; adequate; satisfactory","reading":"じゅうぶん","example":"","exampleTranslation":"","partOfSpeech":"Na-adjective (keiyodoshi)","createdAt":"2025-04-01T12:25:15.279Z"},{"id":4,"deckId":1,"front":"議長","back":"chair; chairman; chairperson; speaker (of an assembly); president (of a council, senate, etc.)","reading":"ぎちょう","example":"議長は辞職します。","exampleTranslation":"The chairman is going to resign.","partOfSpeech":"Noun","createdAt":"2025-04-01T05:37:33.330Z"},{"id":5,"deckId":1,"front":"委員長","back":"chairperson (of a committee); chair; chairman; chairwoman; president","reading":"いいんちょう","example":"彼は委員会の委員長だ。","exampleTranslation":"He's the chairman of the committee.","partOfSpeech":"Noun","createdAt":"2025-04-01T05:37:35.809Z"},{"id":225,"deckId":1,"front":"掛ける","back":"to hang up (e.g. a coat, a picture on the wall); to let hang; to suspend (from); to hoist (e.g. sail); to raise (e.g. flag)","reading":"かける","example":"","exampleTranslation":"","partOfSpeech":"Ichidan verb, Transitive verb","createdAt":"2025-04-04T02:52:28.101Z"},{"id":227,"deckId":1,"front":"賭ける","back":"to wager; to bet; to risk; to stake; to gamble","reading":"かける","example":"","exampleTranslation":"","partOfSpeech":"Ichidan verb, Transitive verb","createdAt":"2025-04-04T02:52:48.308Z"},{"id":226,"deckId":1,"front":"欠ける","back":"to chip; to be chipped; to break (off); to be damaged","reading":"かける","example":"メアリーは配慮に欠ける。","exampleTranslation":"Mary is lacking in delicacy.","partOfSpeech":"Ichidan verb, Intransitive verb","createdAt":"2025-04-04T02:52:33.881Z"},{"id":229,"deckId":1,"front":"学ぶ","back":"to learn; to study; to take lessons in","reading":"まなぶ","example":"人は経験から学ぶ。","exampleTranslation":"People learn from experience.","partOfSpeech":"Godan verb with 'bu' ending, Transitive verb","createdAt":"2025-04-04T04:54:20.295Z"},{"id":228,"deckId":1,"front":"翔る","back":"to soar; to fly","reading":"かける","example":"ボクが憧れたのは翔太部長の『力』じゃない。体を張ってでも信念を貫こうとする雄々しい勇気だったはず。","exampleTranslation":"What I looked up to in Shota was not his 'strength'. It was his heroic courage to put his life on the line to carry out his convictions.","partOfSpeech":"Godan verb with 'ru' ending, Intransitive verb","createdAt":"2025-04-04T02:52:59.159Z"},{"id":10,"deckId":4,"front":"穴","back":"hole; opening; orifice; perforation","reading":"あな","example":"","exampleTranslation":"","partOfSpeech":"Noun","createdAt":"2025-04-01T07:34:01.643Z"},{"id":11,"deckId":4,"front":"油","back":"oil","reading":"あぶら","example":"","exampleTranslation":"","partOfSpeech":"Noun","createdAt":"2025-04-01T07:34:13.392Z"},{"id":12,"deckId":4,"front":"胃","back":"stomach","reading":"い","example":"","exampleTranslation":"","partOfSpeech":"Noun","createdAt":"2025-04-01T07:35:01.228Z"},{"id":13,"deckId":4,"front":"息","back":"breath; breathing","reading":"いき","example":"","exampleTranslation":"","partOfSpeech":"Noun","createdAt":"2025-04-01T07:35:14.938Z"},{"id":14,"deckId":4,"front":"裏","back":"opposite side; bottom; other side; side hidden from view; undersurface; reverse side","reading":"うら","example":"","exampleTranslation":"","partOfSpeech":"Noun","createdAt":"2025-04-01T07:35:28.698Z"},{"id":15,"deckId":4,"front":"噂","back":"rumour; rumor; report; hearsay; gossip; common talk","reading":"うわさ","example":"","exampleTranslation":"","partOfSpeech":"Noun, Suru verb, Noun which may take the genitive case particle 'no'","createdAt":"2025-04-01T07:35:48.891Z"},{"id":16,"deckId":4,"front":"餌","back":"(animal) feed; fodder; pet food","reading":"えさ","example":"","exampleTranslation":"","partOfSpeech":"Noun","createdAt":"2025-04-01T07:36:20.813Z"},{"id":17,"deckId":4,"front":"枝","back":"branch; bough; limb; twig; sprig; spray","reading":"えだ","example":"","exampleTranslation":"","partOfSpeech":"Noun","createdAt":"2025-04-01T07:36:34.874Z"},{"id":18,"deckId":4,"front":"襟","back":"collar; lapel; neckband; neck","reading":"えり","example":"","exampleTranslation":"","partOfSpeech":"Noun","createdAt":"2025-04-01T07:36:47.393Z"},{"id":20,"deckId":4,"front":"親","back":"parent; parents; mother and father","reading":"おや","example":"","exampleTranslation":"","partOfSpeech":"Noun","createdAt":"2025-04-01T07:37:23.702Z"},{"id":21,"deckId":4,"front":"課","back":"lesson","reading":"か","example":"","exampleTranslation":"","partOfSpeech":"Noun, Noun, used as a suffix","createdAt":"2025-04-01T07:37:43.412Z"},{"id":22,"deckId":4,"front":"数","back":"number; amount","reading":"かず","example":"","exampleTranslation":"","partOfSpeech":"Noun","createdAt":"2025-04-01T07:37:57.747Z"},{"id":23,"deckId":4,"front":"形","back":"form; shape; figure","reading":"かたち","example":"","exampleTranslation":"","partOfSpeech":"Noun","createdAt":"2025-04-01T07:38:10.033Z"},{"id":24,"deckId":4,"front":"壁","back":"wall; partition","reading":"かべ","example":"","exampleTranslation":"","partOfSpeech":"Noun","createdAt":"2025-04-01T07:38:22.485Z"},{"id":25,"deckId":4,"front":"雷","back":"lightning; thunder; thunderbolt","reading":"かみなり","example":"","exampleTranslation":"","partOfSpeech":"Noun","createdAt":"2025-04-01T07:38:39.401Z"},{"id":26,"deckId":4,"front":"皮","back":"skin; hide; pelt; fur","reading":"かわ","example":"","exampleTranslation":"","partOfSpeech":"Noun","createdAt":"2025-04-01T07:38:53.926Z"},{"id":27,"deckId":4,"front":"缶","back":"can; tin","reading":"かん","example":"","exampleTranslation":"","partOfSpeech":"Noun, Counter","createdAt":"2025-04-01T07:39:12.735Z"},{"id":28,"deckId":4,"front":"缶","back":"can; tin","reading":"かん","example":"","exampleTranslation":"","partOfSpeech":"Noun, Counter","createdAt":"2025-04-01T07:41:17.634Z"},{"id":29,"deckId":4,"front":"曲","back":"composition; piece of music; song; track (on a record)","reading":"きょく","example":"","exampleTranslation":"","partOfSpeech":"Noun, Noun, used as a suffix","createdAt":"2025-04-01T07:41:32.781Z"},{"id":30,"deckId":4,"front":"雲","back":"cloud","reading":"くも","example":"","exampleTranslation":"","partOfSpeech":"Noun","createdAt":"2025-04-01T07:41:45.567Z"},{"id":31,"deckId":4,"front":"煙","back":"smoke; fumes","reading":"けむり","example":"","exampleTranslation":"","partOfSpeech":"Noun","createdAt":"2025-04-01T07:42:09.071Z"},{"id":32,"deckId":4,"front":"塩","back":"salt; common salt; table salt; sodium chloride","reading":"しお","example":"","exampleTranslation":"","partOfSpeech":"Noun","createdAt":"2025-04-01T07:42:22.861Z"},{"id":33,"deckId":4,"front":"島","back":"island","reading":"しま","example":"","exampleTranslation":"","partOfSpeech":"Noun","createdAt":"2025-04-01T07:42:36.579Z"},{"id":34,"deckId":4,"front":"奥","back":"inner part; interior; back (of a drawer, one's throat, etc.); depths (e.g. of a forest); recesses (e.g. of a cave); heart; end (of a road, garden, etc.)","reading":"おく","example":"","exampleTranslation":"","partOfSpeech":"Noun","createdAt":"2025-04-01T07:48:18.769Z"},{"id":36,"deckId":4,"front":"城","back":"castle","reading":"しろ","example":"","exampleTranslation":"","partOfSpeech":"Noun","createdAt":"2025-04-01T07:53:58.756Z"},{"id":37,"deckId":4,"front":"隅","back":"corner; nook; recess","reading":"すみ","example":"","exampleTranslation":"","partOfSpeech":"Noun, Noun, used as a suffix","createdAt":"2025-04-01T07:54:10.207Z"},{"id":38,"deckId":4,"front":"咳","back":"cough; coughing; tussis","reading":"せき","example":"","exampleTranslation":"","partOfSpeech":"Noun","createdAt":"2025-04-01T07:54:26.638Z"},{"id":39,"deckId":4,"front":"底","back":"bottom; sole","reading":"そこ","example":"","exampleTranslation":"","partOfSpeech":"Noun","createdAt":"2025-04-01T07:54:39.606Z"},{"id":40,"deckId":4,"front":"像","back":"image; figure; statue; picture; portrait","reading":"ぞう","example":"","exampleTranslation":"","partOfSpeech":"Noun, Noun, used as a suffix","createdAt":"2025-04-01T07:54:55.594Z"},{"id":41,"deckId":4,"front":"旅","back":"travel; trip; journey","reading":"たび","example":"","exampleTranslation":"","partOfSpeech":"Noun","createdAt":"2025-04-01T07:55:11.419Z"},{"id":42,"deckId":4,"front":"妻","back":"wife","reading":"つま","example":"","exampleTranslation":"","partOfSpeech":"Noun","createdAt":"2025-04-01T07:55:24.138Z"},{"id":43,"deckId":4,"front":"毒","back":"poison; toxicant","reading":"どく","example":"","exampleTranslation":"","partOfSpeech":"Noun","createdAt":"2025-04-01T07:55:36.078Z"},{"id":44,"deckId":4,"front":"謎","back":"riddle; puzzle; enigma; mystery","reading":"なぞ","example":"","exampleTranslation":"","partOfSpeech":"Noun","createdAt":"2025-04-01T07:55:48.615Z"},{"id":45,"deckId":4,"front":"鍋","back":"pan; pot; saucepan","reading":"なべ","example":"","exampleTranslation":"","partOfSpeech":"Noun","createdAt":"2025-04-01T07:56:03.924Z"},{"id":46,"deckId":4,"front":"波","back":"wave; billow; ripple; breaker; swell","reading":"なみ","example":"","exampleTranslation":"","partOfSpeech":"Noun","createdAt":"2025-04-01T07:56:17.598Z"},{"id":47,"deckId":4,"front":"涙","back":"tear; tears; lachrymal secretion","reading":"なみだ","example":"","exampleTranslation":"","partOfSpeech":"Noun","createdAt":"2025-04-01T07:56:27.915Z"},{"id":48,"deckId":4,"front":"庭","back":"garden; yard; courtyard","reading":"にわ","example":"","exampleTranslation":"","partOfSpeech":"Noun","createdAt":"2025-04-01T07:56:43.399Z"},{"id":49,"deckId":4,"front":"熱","back":"heat","reading":"ねつ","example":"","exampleTranslation":"","partOfSpeech":"Noun","createdAt":"2025-04-01T07:56:54.527Z"},{"id":50,"deckId":4,"front":"箸","back":"chopsticks","reading":"はし","example":"","exampleTranslation":"","partOfSpeech":"Noun","createdAt":"2025-04-01T07:57:07.852Z"},{"id":51,"deckId":4,"front":"畑","back":"field (for growing wheat, fruit, vegetables, etc.); cultivated land; vegetable plot; kitchen garden; plantation","reading":"はたけ","example":"","exampleTranslation":"","partOfSpeech":"Noun","createdAt":"2025-04-01T07:57:28.779Z"},{"id":52,"deckId":4,"front":"羽","back":"feather; plume; down","reading":"はね","example":"","exampleTranslation":"","partOfSpeech":"Noun","createdAt":"2025-04-01T07:57:42.773Z"},{"id":53,"deckId":4,"front":"幅","back":"width; breadth","reading":"はば","example":"","exampleTranslation":"","partOfSpeech":"Noun","createdAt":"2025-04-01T08:01:07.236Z"},{"id":54,"deckId":4,"front":"膝","back":"knee","reading":"ひざ","example":"","exampleTranslation":"","partOfSpeech":"Noun","createdAt":"2025-04-01T08:01:18.808Z"},{"id":55,"deckId":4,"front":"骨","back":"bone","reading":"ほね","example":"","exampleTranslation":"","partOfSpeech":"Noun","createdAt":"2025-04-01T08:01:27.303Z"},{"id":56,"deckId":4,"front":"棒","back":"pole; rod; stick; baton","reading":"ぼう","example":"","exampleTranslation":"","partOfSpeech":"Noun","createdAt":"2025-04-01T08:01:38.585Z"},{"id":57,"deckId":4,"front":"孫","back":"grandchild","reading":"まご","example":"","exampleTranslation":"","partOfSpeech":"Noun","createdAt":"2025-04-01T08:01:50.635Z"},{"id":59,"deckId":4,"front":"街","back":"street; quarter; district; area","reading":"がい","example":"","exampleTranslation":"","partOfSpeech":"Noun, used as a suffix","createdAt":"2025-04-02T01:47:28.497Z"},{"id":60,"deckId":4,"front":"湖","back":"lake","reading":"みずうみ","example":"","exampleTranslation":"","partOfSpeech":"Noun","createdAt":"2025-04-02T01:47:47.227Z"},{"id":61,"deckId":4,"front":"娘","back":"daughter","reading":"むすめ","example":"","exampleTranslation":"","partOfSpeech":"Noun","createdAt":"2025-04-02T01:48:03.739Z"},{"id":62,"deckId":4,"front":"胸","back":"chest; breast","reading":"むね","example":"","exampleTranslation":"","partOfSpeech":"Noun","createdAt":"2025-04-02T01:48:36.311Z"},{"id":63,"deckId":4,"front":"床","back":"floor","reading":"ゆか","example":"","exampleTranslation":"","partOfSpeech":"Noun","createdAt":"2025-04-02T01:48:59.116Z"},{"id":64,"deckId":4,"front":"夢","back":"dream","reading":"ゆめ","example":"","exampleTranslation":"","partOfSpeech":"Noun","createdAt":"2025-04-02T01:49:16.297Z"},{"id":65,"deckId":4,"front":"量","back":"quantity; amount; volume; capacity; portion (of food)","reading":"りょう","example":"","exampleTranslation":"","partOfSpeech":"Noun, Noun, used as a suffix","createdAt":"2025-04-02T01:49:45.457Z"},{"id":66,"deckId":4,"front":"寮","back":"hostel; dormitory","reading":"りょう","example":"","exampleTranslation":"","partOfSpeech":"Noun","createdAt":"2025-04-02T01:49:49.926Z"},{"id":67,"deckId":4,"front":"列","back":"row; line; file; column; queue; rank; procession","reading":"れつ","example":"","exampleTranslation":"","partOfSpeech":"Noun","createdAt":"2025-04-02T01:50:34.000Z"},{"id":68,"deckId":4,"front":"合図","back":"sign; signal; cue","reading":"あいず","example":"","exampleTranslation":"","partOfSpeech":"Noun, Suru verb, Transitive verb, Intransitive verb","createdAt":"2025-04-02T01:50:44.948Z"},{"id":69,"deckId":4,"front":"青空","back":"blue sky","reading":"あおぞら","example":"","exampleTranslation":"","partOfSpeech":"Noun","createdAt":"2025-04-02T01:50:55.818Z"},{"id":70,"deckId":4,"front":"以外","back":"excluding; except (for); apart from; other than; besides; in addition to","reading":"いがい","example":"","exampleTranslation":"","partOfSpeech":"Noun, used as a suffix","createdAt":"2025-04-02T01:51:20.759Z"},{"id":71,"deckId":4,"front":"以後","back":"after this; from now on; hereafter","reading":"いご","example":"","exampleTranslation":"","partOfSpeech":"Noun, Adverb (fukushi)","createdAt":"2025-04-02T01:51:28.727Z"},{"id":72,"deckId":4,"front":"以降","back":"on and after; from ... onward; since","reading":"いこう","example":"","exampleTranslation":"","partOfSpeech":"Noun, Adverb (fukushi)","createdAt":"2025-04-02T01:51:43.607Z"},{"id":73,"deckId":4,"front":"維持","back":"maintenance; preservation; improvement","reading":"いじ","example":"","exampleTranslation":"","partOfSpeech":"Noun, Suru verb, Transitive verb","createdAt":"2025-04-02T01:52:24.645Z"},{"id":74,"deckId":4,"front":"意識","back":"consciousness","reading":"いしき","example":"","exampleTranslation":"","partOfSpeech":"Noun, Suru verb","createdAt":"2025-04-02T01:52:36.096Z"},{"id":75,"deckId":4,"front":"以前","back":"before; prior to; ago","reading":"いぜん","example":"","exampleTranslation":"","partOfSpeech":"Noun, used as a suffix","createdAt":"2025-04-02T01:52:45.868Z"},{"id":76,"deckId":4,"front":"位置","back":"place; position; location","reading":"いち","example":"","exampleTranslation":"","partOfSpeech":"Noun, Suru verb, Intransitive verb","createdAt":"2025-04-02T01:52:56.873Z"},{"id":77,"deckId":4,"front":"一流","back":"first-class; first-rate; top-flight; top-ranking; leading; eminent; top","reading":"いちりゅう","example":"","exampleTranslation":"","partOfSpeech":"Noun which may take the genitive case particle 'no', Noun","createdAt":"2025-04-02T01:53:08.928Z"},{"id":78,"deckId":4,"front":"一般","back":"general; universal","reading":"いっぱん","example":"","exampleTranslation":"","partOfSpeech":"Noun which may take the genitive case particle 'no', Noun","createdAt":"2025-04-02T01:53:23.343Z"},{"id":79,"deckId":4,"front":"移動","back":"movement; transfer; migration; removal; travel","reading":"いどう","example":"","exampleTranslation":"","partOfSpeech":"Noun, Suru verb, Transitive verb, Intransitive verb","createdAt":"2025-04-02T01:53:33.432Z"},{"id":80,"deckId":4,"front":"以内","back":"within; inside of; less than","reading":"いない","example":"","exampleTranslation":"","partOfSpeech":"Noun, Noun, used as a suffix, Adverb (fukushi)","createdAt":"2025-04-02T01:53:43.143Z"},{"id":81,"deckId":4,"front":"田舎","back":"rural area; countryside; the sticks","reading":"いなか","example":"","exampleTranslation":"","partOfSpeech":"Noun","createdAt":"2025-04-02T01:53:57.375Z"},{"id":82,"deckId":4,"front":"印刷","back":"printing","reading":"いんさつ","example":"","exampleTranslation":"","partOfSpeech":"Noun, Suru verb, Transitive verb","createdAt":"2025-04-02T01:54:07.745Z"},{"id":83,"deckId":4,"front":"印象","back":"impression","reading":"いんしょう","example":"","exampleTranslation":"","partOfSpeech":"Noun","createdAt":"2025-04-02T01:54:17.056Z"},{"id":84,"deckId":4,"front":"飲料","back":"beverage; drink","reading":"いんりょう","example":"","exampleTranslation":"","partOfSpeech":"Noun","createdAt":"2025-04-02T01:54:27.280Z"},{"id":85,"deckId":4,"front":"内側","back":"inside; interior; inner part","reading":"うちがわ","example":"","exampleTranslation":"","partOfSpeech":"Noun, Noun which may take the genitive case particle 'no'","createdAt":"2025-04-02T01:54:41.546Z"},{"id":86,"deckId":4,"front":"宇宙","back":"universe; cosmos; space","reading":"うちゅう","example":"","exampleTranslation":"","partOfSpeech":"Noun","createdAt":"2025-04-02T01:54:58.786Z"},{"id":87,"deckId":4,"front":"影響","back":"influence; effect; impact","reading":"えいきょう","example":"","exampleTranslation":"","partOfSpeech":"Noun, Suru verb, Intransitive verb","createdAt":"2025-04-02T01:55:18.682Z"},{"id":88,"deckId":4,"front":"営業","back":"business; trade; operations","reading":"えいぎょう","example":"","exampleTranslation":"","partOfSpeech":"Noun, Suru verb, Transitive verb","createdAt":"2025-04-02T01:55:28.960Z"},{"id":89,"deckId":4,"front":"笑顔","back":"smiling face; smile","reading":"えがお","example":"","exampleTranslation":"","partOfSpeech":"Noun","createdAt":"2025-04-02T01:55:40.556Z"},{"id":90,"deckId":4,"front":"延期","back":"postponement; deferment; adjournment","reading":"えんき","example":"","exampleTranslation":"","partOfSpeech":"Noun, Suru verb, Transitive verb","createdAt":"2025-04-02T01:55:53.945Z"},{"id":91,"deckId":4,"front":"演奏","back":"musical performance","reading":"えんそう","example":"","exampleTranslation":"","partOfSpeech":"Noun, Suru verb, Transitive verb","createdAt":"2025-04-02T01:56:07.881Z"},{"id":92,"deckId":4,"front":"遠慮","back":"reserve; constraint; restraint; modesty; diffidence; hesitation; holding back; discretion; tact; thoughtfulness","reading":"えんりょ","example":"","exampleTranslation":"","partOfSpeech":"Noun, Suru verb","createdAt":"2025-04-02T01:56:21.957Z"},{"id":93,"deckId":4,"front":"往復","back":"making a round trip; going and returning; coming and going","reading":"おうふく","example":"","exampleTranslation":"","partOfSpeech":"Noun, Suru verb, Intransitive verb","createdAt":"2025-04-02T01:56:34.359Z"},{"id":94,"deckId":4,"front":"応募","back":"application; subscription; entry (competition, raffle, etc.); enlistment","reading":"おうぼ","example":"","exampleTranslation":"","partOfSpeech":"Noun, Suru verb, Transitive verb, Intransitive verb","createdAt":"2025-04-02T01:56:47.023Z"},{"id":95,"deckId":4,"front":"応用","back":"(practical) application; putting to practical use","reading":"おうよう","example":"","exampleTranslation":"","partOfSpeech":"Noun, Suru verb, Transitive verb","createdAt":"2025-04-02T01:56:56.880Z"},{"id":96,"deckId":4,"front":"大勢","back":"crowd of people; great number of people","reading":"おおぜい","example":"","exampleTranslation":"","partOfSpeech":"Noun, Noun which may take the genitive case particle 'no'","createdAt":"2025-04-02T01:57:08.407Z"},{"id":97,"deckId":4,"front":"親子","back":"parent and child","reading":"おやこ","example":"","exampleTranslation":"","partOfSpeech":"Noun","createdAt":"2025-04-02T01:57:19.842Z"},{"id":98,"deckId":4,"front":"温泉","back":"hot spring","reading":"おんせん","example":"","exampleTranslation":"","partOfSpeech":"Noun","createdAt":"2025-04-02T01:57:28.570Z"},{"id":99,"deckId":4,"front":"会員","back":"member; the membership","reading":"かいいん","example":"","exampleTranslation":"","partOfSpeech":"Noun","createdAt":"2025-04-02T01:57:38.508Z"},{"id":100,"deckId":4,"front":"絵画","back":"painting; picture","reading":"かいが","example":"","exampleTranslation":"","partOfSpeech":"Noun","createdAt":"2025-04-02T01:57:48.281Z"},{"id":101,"deckId":4,"front":"会議","back":"meeting; conference; session; assembly; council; convention; congress","reading":"かいぎ","example":"","exampleTranslation":"","partOfSpeech":"Noun, Suru verb, Intransitive verb, Transitive verb","createdAt":"2025-04-02T01:57:55.675Z"},{"id":102,"deckId":4,"front":"会計","back":"accounting; finance; account; reckoning","reading":"かいけい","example":"","exampleTranslation":"","partOfSpeech":"Noun, Noun which may take the genitive case particle 'no', Suru verb","createdAt":"2025-04-02T01:58:07.508Z"},{"id":103,"deckId":4,"front":"解決","back":"settlement; solution; resolution","reading":"かいけつ","example":"","exampleTranslation":"","partOfSpeech":"Noun, Suru verb, Transitive verb, Intransitive verb","createdAt":"2025-04-02T01:58:17.737Z"},{"id":104,"deckId":4,"front":"回収","back":"collection; recovery; withdrawal; retrieval","reading":"かいしゅう","example":"","exampleTranslation":"","partOfSpeech":"Noun, Suru verb, Transitive verb","createdAt":"2025-04-02T01:58:27.887Z"},{"id":105,"deckId":4,"front":"開始","back":"start; commencement; beginning; initiation","reading":"かいし","example":"","exampleTranslation":"","partOfSpeech":"Noun, Suru verb, Transitive verb, Intransitive verb","createdAt":"2025-04-02T01:58:39.324Z"},{"id":106,"deckId":4,"front":"開場","back":"opening (the doors of a venue)","reading":"かいじょう","example":"","exampleTranslation":"","partOfSpeech":"Noun, Suru verb, Intransitive verb","createdAt":"2025-04-02T01:58:49.473Z"},{"id":107,"deckId":4,"front":"回数","back":"number of times; frequency; count","reading":"かいすう","example":"","exampleTranslation":"","partOfSpeech":"Noun","createdAt":"2025-04-02T01:59:00.196Z"},{"id":108,"deckId":4,"front":"解説","back":"explanation; commentary; exposition; elucidation","reading":"かいせつ","example":"","exampleTranslation":"","partOfSpeech":"Noun, Suru verb, Transitive verb","createdAt":"2025-04-02T01:59:09.883Z"},{"id":109,"deckId":4,"front":"階段","back":"stairs; stairway; staircase","reading":"かいだん","example":"","exampleTranslation":"","partOfSpeech":"Noun","createdAt":"2025-04-02T01:59:18.962Z"},{"id":110,"deckId":4,"front":"開店","back":"opening a new shop","reading":"かいてん","example":"","exampleTranslation":"","partOfSpeech":"Noun, Suru verb, Transitive verb, Intransitive verb","createdAt":"2025-04-02T01:59:28.543Z"},{"id":111,"deckId":4,"front":"価格","back":"price; value; cost","reading":"かかく","example":"","exampleTranslation":"","partOfSpeech":"Noun","createdAt":"2025-04-02T01:59:39.433Z"},{"id":112,"deckId":4,"front":"奥","back":"inner part; interior; back (of a drawer, one's throat, etc.); depths (e.g. of a forest); recesses (e.g. of a cave); heart; end (of a road, garden, etc.)","reading":"おく","example":"","exampleTranslation":"","partOfSpeech":"Noun","createdAt":"2025-04-02T02:00:22.514Z"},{"id":113,"deckId":4,"front":"城","back":"castle","reading":"しろ","example":"","exampleTranslation":"","partOfSpeech":"Noun","createdAt":"2025-04-02T02:00:34.737Z"}]